Elizabeth Ireland

Digital marketing manager, content marketing specialist, and technical writer with 9+ years experience. After close to a decade in my current field, I'm making great strides to pivot my career to that of tech. After finishing a 6 month coding bootcamp, I'm ready to embark on a new path.

Long Beach, CA 808.954.9655

liz.t.ireland@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/elizabeth-tozlian-ireland https://liztireland.iournoportfolio.com/

EXPERIENCE

Service Champions, Brea, CA — Content Marketing Manager

August 2019 - Present

- Create, edit, and debug HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code for consumer facing websites
- Write and manage SEO optimized content for 7+ companies
- Manage a team of freelance writers to produce 30+ pieces of content per month
- Create onboarding and training materials for new marketing hires
- Code and deploy 7+ consumer facing email newsletters per month

Apartment SEO, Long Beach, CA — *Social Media Manager*

March 2019 - July 2019

- Managed social media ad campaigns for 30+ clients
- Optimized 120+ blogs per month with SEO best practices
- Scheduled daily social media updates and wrote content for 100+ clients
- Researched and developed SEO tactics based on trends and data

ARK Crystal, San Clemente, CA — Digital Marketing Specialist

August 2018 - March 2019

- Established an effective social media plan based on consumer behavior and analytics
- Created first year benchmarks for a brand new company
- · Constructed a social media plan for a variety of platforms

U.S. Farmers & Ranchers Alliance, St. Louis, MO — *Digital Marketing Manager*

August 2016 - August 2018

- Created and implemented digital strategies to promote events, blog posts, email newsletters, and online content across a variety of social media platforms
- Managed the creation and editorial of press releases, op-eds, and website content
- Provided daily social listening reports for staff and key stakeholders
- Led a small team to create and promote an advocacy based communications app

American Optometric Association, St. Louis, MO — *Content Coordinator*

October 2014 - August 2016

- Developed and executed email campaigns averaging 35-65k recipients
- Authored training materials for email marketing platforms
- Made email deployment decisions based on website and email analytics
- Managed and created content for aoa.org and affiliated social media channels
- Edited medical textbooks for optometry students

SKILLS

- Front End Developer
 High-quality content creation
- Copywriting and editing
- Reporting, interviewing, and storytelling
- Social Media Platforms
- Salesforce/CRM software
- Social media and website analytics
- SEO best practices
- Adobe Creative Suite and Microsoft programs
- CMS Platforms: Wordpress, Druple, Ingeniux
- Email marketing platforms:

Adestra, High Road, Constant

Contact, Mail Chimp

- Event coordination
- Project management

Education

December 2021

UC Irvine, CA — Certificate Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

June 2012

San Francisco State University, CA — *B.A. Journalism*

June 2009

Foothill College, CA — A.A. Social Sciences